

# NICK LORENZIN

TECHNOLOGY EXECUTIVE
& INNOVATION PIONEER

14316 Talawa Dr Oregon City, OR 97045

t: 503-929-8491

e: nicholas.lorenzini@gmail.com

#### PROFILE



14 years of increasing technology leadership and management responsibilities, shaping strategic priorities and competitive alignment for non-profit and public sector enterprises.



Over 20 years of varied development experiences in functional and prototypal languages, to leading large dev teams to build multi-million dollar, modern, single-page apps in highly-political, enterprise organizations.



Strong passion for building team cultures - changing the hearts & minds of diverse teams, under one vision.

# **EDUCATION**



#### M.S. IT Management

Western Governors University 2018 - 2019



#### M.S. Strategic Security

National American University 2010 - 2013



#### **B.S. Intelligence Management**

National American University 2009 - 2010

### CERTIFICATIONS



Project Management
Professional (PMP)
Project Management



Certified Chief Information
Security Officer (C|CISO)
EC-Council



Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)
EC-Council

#### HIGHLIGHTS



Led the nation's largest non-profit healthcare provider in adopting modern frontend libraries (React & Redux) to meet modern user product expectations.



Authored a 5-year strategic IT vision for the US Department of Agriculture's programming of an annual \$500 million (taxpayer) technology budget.



Postured the US Forest Service to absorb an annual 10% IT budget reduction without loss of user capabilities, through automation and modernization.



Directed the successful migration of a 60+ unique web application suite to a PaaS environment.



Founded the Defense Information Systems Agency's first all-Reserve Servicemember Cyber Defense Detachments.



Cyber Security Author of the 2015 National Infrastructure Protection Plan 
Government Facilities Sector-Specific Plan, a White House-issued policy.

# **HOW I SPEND MY WORK DAY**



Maximizing Release Periods



**Bulldozing Bad Processes** 



Promoting a Trust-based Culture



Building Brand Pride of Ownership



Accelerating Development



Improving People & Tech



Growing Enterprise Scalability



Solution Engineering



Having fun :-)

# EXPERIENCE

#### Sr. Manager, IT Engineering Applications

Kaiser Permanente / June 2019 - Present

Development Manager for Customers & Contracts - a new app for creating & managing healthcare membership contracts across 9 regions of service. This application served as a critical component in a billion dollar IT investment to integrate membership systems across 9 Kaiser regions (nationally) utilizing modern libraries and architecture.

# **Application Development & Operations Program Lead**

United States Forest Service / June 2015 - June 2019

Managed over sixty unique Natural Resource Management applications and their environments (cloud and on-premise service). Led over sixty mixed resources (employees and consultant) for both application development, architecture, database administration and testing teams in support of Forest Service operational needs.

# Assistant Director for Strategic Planning, Information Management & Architecture - Temporary Promotion

US Department of Agriculture - Natural Resources & Environment Mission Area / May 2018 - September 2018 Lead for strategic planning and execution of a \$450 million dollar IT budget in support of application development, technology and

communication infrastructure across the US Forest Service. Negotiating agent for technology governance committees and agency executives.



14316 Talawa Dr Oregon City, OR 97045

t: 503-929-8491

e: nicholas.lorenzini@gmail.com

# A FEW MORE EXPERIENCES >>

# **Policy Program Manager**

Department of Homeland Security / November 2014 - June 2015

Lead for the Federal Protective Service's delegations of authority program, which provides delegated-Constitutional authority for Federal Departments and agencies to conduct both law enforcement and security activities. Contributing policy analyst for cyber security in protection of Federal facilities and infrastructure across the United States.

#### **IT Program Manager**

Defense Technical Information Center / December 2012 - November 2014

Program and Development Manager for a multi-million dollar, multi-year program to develop a first-of-kind government identity management solution to provide access to both unclassified and classified research & engineering data, and collaboration platforms.

#### Requirements Analyst - Consultant

Joint Chief of Staff, MYMIC LLC / February 2012 - Decemer 2012

Lead requirements analyst for reviewing military service and agency submissions to address gaps and capability needs within cyber, biometrics, force protection and IT programs. Requirements analysis would lead to the decision-support for establishment, continuation and or closure of major acquisition programs (multi-billion dollar, multi-year programs).

#### **Other Various Positions - Consultant**

MYMIC LLC, DISYS LLC / June 2011 - February 2012

Work involved roles served for both the Joint Chiefs of Staff (J8) and Headquarters - US Army (HQDA) within the Pentagon in support of national security, and acquisition program support.

#### MILITARY EXPERIENCE

Specialties: Cyber Defense, Communications, Logistics, Physical Security, Conflict Resolution

#### Captain (O-3)

US Army Inactive Ready Reserves (Present) US Army Ready Reserves (2012-2017) US Marine Corps (2006-2011)

#### Organizations:

Defense Information Systems Agency, Defense Threat Reduction Agency, Army 364 Civil Affairs Brigade, LOGCAP Logistics Support

# Locations:

Jordan, Israel, Switzerland, Phillippines, France, Germany, Honduras, Japan

### SPECIALTY SCHOOLS



**USDA IT Fellowship Cohort** US Department of Agriculture 2018



Signal Corps Officer Leadership **US Army** Signal Corps Fort Gordon 2013



Marine Security Guard School **US Marine Corps Embassy Security Group** 2007

# LEADERSHIP PHILOSOPHY



Finding balance has been critical for my teams to be at their best. It's bigger than work/life, but ensuring health (physical, mental and spiritual) is balanced. Every individual is different and can take stress on different.



Building Agile culture wherever I'm at to engrain making change an every day norm. A culture of change dominates the market, and thrives on complex challenges. If I find a culture that is change adverse, I take it to heart to build elasticity and create an environment for continuous learning and inclusion.



Empowering others is one my favorite duties as a leader. I get to show the trust and commitment I have for my teams when I entrust them. One of the first things engrained in me as a professional - everyone is a leader. I rely heavily on teams and delegate in a trust-based environment

# **DEV SKILLS**



Angular

HTML5

CSS<sub>3</sub>

Java/J2EE

# STRATEGY & POLICY

Vision Setting HIPAA Strategic Planning PCI-DSS IT Governance SOX Build vs. Buy Resource Strategies Workforce Evolution Continuity Planning Vendor Management Enterprise Architecture

# TECH EXPERIENCES

BACKEND: **TESTING:** LIBRARIES: React.js Node.js Enzyme Redux.js Firebase Jest Django-REST Mocha Angular.js OAuth 2.0 **Jenkins** Vue.js Anime.js Next.is SonarQube GraphQL Gatsby.js Spring Cloud

# VOLUNTEER/GIVING

#### **State-certified Foster Parent**

State of Oregon 2016 - Present

#### **Board Member & Basketball Coach**

**HOOPS** Basketball League

2019 - Present